<TABLE_DEFINITIONS Table="CA4" Name="Personal Income and Employment by Major Component" Source="USDOC/BEA/RD"><LINE><Code>10</Code><Description>Personal income (thousands of dollars)</Description><Definition>Personal income is the income received by persons from participation in production, plus transfer receipts from government and business, plus government interest (which is treated like a transfer receipt). It is defined as the sum of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, proprietors' income with inventory valuation and capital consumption adjustments, rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment, personal dividend income, personal interest income, and personal current transfer receipts, less contributions for government social insurance. Because the personal income of an area represents the income that is received by, or on behalf of, all the persons who live in that area, and because the estimates of some components of personal income (wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, and contributions for government social insurance) are made on a place-of-work basis, state personal income includes an adjustment for residence. The residence adjustment represents the net flow of compensation (less contributions for government social insurance) of interstate commuters.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>11</Code><Description>Nonfarm personal income</Description><Definition>Nonfarm Personal Income is Personal Income minus Farm Income.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>12</Code><Description>Farm income</Description><Definition>Farm income is the sum of wages and salaries, employer contributions for employee pension and insurance funds, and proprietors' income in the farm industry. It comprises the net income of sole proprietors, partners, and hired laborers arising directly from the current production of agricultural commodities, both livestock and crops, and specifically excludes the income of non-family farm corporations.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>20</Code><Description>Population (persons)</Description><Definition>Number of individuals (both civilian and military) who reside in an area as of July 1. BEA uses the Census Bureau's midyear population estimates.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>30</Code><Description>Per capita personal income (dollars)</Description><Definition>This measure of income is calculated as the total personal income of the residents of an area divided by the population of the area. Per capita personal income is often used as an indicator of consumers' purchasing power and of the economic well-being of the residents of an area.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>35</Code><Description>Earnings by place of work</Description><Definition>Earnings by place of work is the sum of three components of personal income-wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, and proprietors' income. See also Net earnings by place of residence and Net labor earnings. BEA presents earnings by place of work because it can be used in the analyses of regional economies as a proxy for the income that is generated from participation in current production.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>36</Code><Description>Less: Contributions for government social insurance</Description><Definition>These contributions, which are subtracted in the calculation of personal income, consist of employee and self-employed contributions for government social insurance and employer contributions for government social insurance.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>37</Code><Description>Employee and self-employed contributions for government social insurance</Description><Definition>Employee and self-employed contributions for government social insurance (formerly called personal contributions for government social insurance) consist of the contributions, or payments, by employees, by the self-employed, and by other individuals who participate in the following government programs: Social Security (Old-age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance); Hospital Insurance (Medicare Part A); Supplementary Medical Insurance (Medicare Parts B and D); unemployment insurance; railroad retirement; veterans' life insurance; and temporary disability insurance. These contributions are excluded from personal income by definition, but the components of personal income upon which these contributions are based-- mainly wages and salaries and proprietors' income-- are presented gross of these contributions. See also Earnings by place of work, Net labor earnings, and Personal income.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>38</Code><Description>Employer contributions for government social insurance</Description><Definition>Employer contributions for government social insurance is a component of earnings and compensation. It consists of employer payments under the following federal and state and local government programs: Social Security (Old-age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance (OASDI)); Hospital Insurance (HI); unemployment insurance; railroad retirement; pension benefit guaranty; veterans' life insurance; publicly-administered workers' compensation; military medical insurance; and temporary disability insurance. These contributions are excluded from personal income by definition, but as part of supplements to wages and salaries, they are included in earnings by place of work and compensation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>42</Code><Description>Plus: Adjustment for residence</Description><Definition>The adjustment for residence is the net flow of the net labor earnings of interarea commuters. The state and county estimates of personal income are presented by the state and county of residence of the income recipients. However, the source data for most of the components of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, and contributions for government social insurance are on a place-of-work basis. Consequently, a residence adjustment is made to convert the estimates based on these source data to a place-of-residence basis.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>45</Code><Description>Equals: Net earnings by place of residence</Description><Definition>Net earnings by place of residence is earnings by place of work-the sum of wages and salaries, supplements to wages and salaries, and proprietors' income-less contributions for government social insurance, plus an adjustment to convert earnings by place of work to a place of residence basis.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>46</Code><Description>Plus: Dividends, interest, and rent</Description><Definition>Personal dividend income, personal interest income, and rental income of persons with capital consumption adjustment are sometimes referred to as "investment income" or "property income."Dividends: This component of personal income consists of the payments in cash or other assets, excluding the corporation's own stock, made by corporations located in the United States or abroad to persons who are U.S. residents. It excludes that portion of dividends paid by regulated investment companies (mutual funds) related to capital gains distributions. Interest: This component of personal income is the interest income (monetary and imputed) of persons from all sources. Rent: Rental income is the net income of persons from the rental of real property except for the income of persons primarily engaged in the real estate business; the imputed net rental income of the owner-occupants of nonfarm dwellings; and the royalties received from patents, copyrights, and the right to natural resources.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>47</Code><Description>Plus: Personal current transfer receipts</Description><Definition>This component of personal income is payments to persons for which no current services are performed. It consists of payments to individuals and to nonprofit institutions by Federal, state, and local governments and by businesses.  Government payments to individuals includes retirement and disability insurance benefits, medical payments (mainly Medicare and Medicaid), income maintenance benefits, unemployment insurance compensation, veterans benefits, and Federal grants and loans to students. Government payments to nonprofit institutions excludes payments by the Federal Government for work under research and development contracts. Business payments to persons consists primarily of liability payments for personal injury and of corporate gifts to nonprofit institutions.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>50</Code><Description>Wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Wages and salaries are broadly defined to include commissions, tips, and bonuses; voluntary employee contributions to deferred compensation plans, such as 401(k) plans; employee gains from exercising stock options; and receipts-in-kind that represent income. Wages and salaries are measured before deductions, such as social security contributions, union dues, and voluntary employee contributions to defined contribution pension plans. They represent the amount of wages and salaries accrued during the year.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>60</Code><Description>Supplements to wages and salaries</Description><Definition>Supplements to wages and salaries consists of employer contributions for government social insurance and employer contributions for employee pension and insurance funds.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>61</Code><Description>Employer contributions for employee pension and insurance funds</Description><Definition>Employer contributions for employee pension and insurance funds consists of employer payments to private and government employee retirement plans, private group health and life insurance plans, privately administered workers' compensation plans, and supplemental unemployment benefit plans. It was formerly called other labor income.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>62</Code><Description>Employer contributions for government social insurance</Description><Definition>Employer contributions for government social insurance is a component of earnings and compensation. It consists of employer payments under the following federal and state and local government programs: Social Security (Old-age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance (OASDI)); Hospital Insurance (HI); unemployment insurance; railroad retirement; pension benefit guaranty; veterans' life insurance; publicly-administered workers' compensation; military medical insurance; and temporary disability insurance. These contributions are excluded from personal income by definition, but as part of supplements to wages and salaries, they are included in earnings by place of work and compensation.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>70</Code><Description>Proprietors' income</Description><Definition>Proprietors' income with inventory valuation and capital consumption adjustments is the current-production income (including income in kind) of sole proprietorships, partnerships, and tax-exempt cooperatives. Corporate directors' fees are included in proprietors' income. Proprietors' income includes the interest income received by financial partnerships and the net rental real estate income of those partnerships primarily engaged in the real estate business.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>71</Code><Description>Farm proprietors' income</Description><Definition>Farm proprietors' income consists of the income that is received by the sole proprietorships and the partnerships that operate farms. It excludes the income that is received by corporate farms.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>72</Code><Description>Nonfarm proprietors' income</Description><Definition>Nonfarm Proprietors' Income consists of the income that is received by nonfarm sole proprietorships and partnerships and the income that is received by tax-exempt cooperatives.  The national estimates of nonfarm proprietors' income are primarily derived from income tax data. Because these data do not always reflect current production and because they are incomplete, the estimates also include four major adjustments--the inventory valuation adjustment, the capital consumption adjustment, the "misreporting" adjustment, and the adjustment for the net margins on owner-built housing. The inventory valuation adjustment offsets the effects of the gains and the losses that result from changes in the prices of products withdrawn from inventories; this adjustment for recent years has been small, but it is important to the definition of proprietors' income. The capital consumption adjustment changes the value of the consumption, or depreciation, of fixed capital from the historical-cost basis used in the source data to a replacement-cost basis. The "misreporting" adjustment adds an estimate of the income of sole proprietors and partnerships that is not reported on tax returns. The adjustment for the net margins on owner-built housing is an addition to the estimate for the construction industry. It is the imputed net income of individuals from the construction or renovation of their own dwellings.  The source data necessary to prepare these adjustments are available only at the national level. Therefore, the national estimates of nonfarm proprietors' income that include the adjustments are allocated to states, and these state estimates are allocated to the counties, in proportion to tax return data that do not reflect the adjustments.  In addition, the national estimates include adjustments made to reflect decreases in monetary and imputed income that result from damage to fixed capital and to inventories that is caused by disasters, such as hurricanes, floods, and earthquakes. These adjustments are attributed to states and counties on the basis of information from the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>7010</Code><Description>Total employment</Description><Definition>The BEA employment series for states and local areas comprises estimates of the number of jobs, full-time plus part-time, by place of work. Full-time and part-time jobs are counted at equal weight. Employees, sole proprietors, and active partners are included, but unpaid family workers and volunteers are not included. Proprietors employment consists of the number of sole proprietorships and the number of partners in partnerships. The description "by place of work" applies to the wage and salary portion of the series and, with relatively little error, to the entire series. The proprietors employment portion of the series, however, is more nearly by place of residence because, for nonfarm sole proprietorships, the estimates are based on IRS tax data that reflect the address from which the proprietor's individual tax return is filed, which is usually the proprietor's residence. The nonfarm partnership portion of the proprietors employment series reflects the tax-filing address of the partnership, which may be either the residence of one of the partners or the business address of the partnership. The employment estimates are designed to be consistent with the estimates of wages and salaries and proprietors' income that are part of the personal income series. The employment estimates are based on the same sets of source data as the corresponding earnings estimates and are prepared with parallel methodologies. Two forms of proprietors' income-the income of limited partnerships and the income of tax-exempt cooperatives-have no corresponding employment estimates.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>7020</Code><Description>Wage and salary employment</Description><Definition>Wage and salary employment, also referred to as wage and salary jobs, measures the average annual number of full-time and part-time jobs in each area by place-of-work. All jobs for which wages and salaries are paid are counted. Full-time and part-time jobs are counted with equal weight. Jury and witness service, as well as paid employment of prisoners, are not counted as wage and salary employment; the payments for these activities are classified as "other labor income" in the personal income measure. Corporate directorships are counted as self-employment.</Definition></LINE><LINE><Code>7040</Code><Description>Proprietors employment</Description><Definition>Proprietors employment includes both nonfarm proprietors and farm proprietors.Nonfarm proprietors:The BEA local area estimates of nonfarm self-employment consist of the number of sole proprietorships and the number of individual business partners not assumed to be limited partners. The nonfarm self-employment estimates resemble the wage and salary employment estimates in that both series measure jobs--as opposed to workers--on a full-time and part-time basis. However, because of limitations in source data, two important measurement differences exist between the two sets of estimates. First, the self-employment estimates are largely on a place-of-residence basis rather than on the preferred place-of-work basis. Second, the self-employment estimates reflect the total number of sole proprietorships or partnerships active at any time during the year--as opposed to the annual average measure used for wage and salary employment. Farm proprietors:Farm self-employment is defined as the number of non-corporate farm operators, consisting of sole proprietors and partners. A farm is defined as an establishment that produces, or normally would be expected to produce, at least $1,000 worth of farm products--crops and livestock--in a typical year. Because of the low cutoff point for this definition, the farm self-employment estimates are effectively on a full-time and part-time basis. The estimates are consistent with the job-count basis of the estimates of wage and salary employment because farm proprietors are counted without regard to any other employment. The distinction between place-of-work and place-of-residence is not significant because most farmers live on or near their land. Similarly, because of the annual production cycle of most farming, the distinctions between the point-in-time, the average annual, and the any-activity temporal concepts of employment measurement are not significant.</Definition></LINE></TABLE_DEFINITIONS>
